<section title="Format and Content of Internet Drafts (Future)">

<t>[[[ This section describes a future where the v3 format will be allowed as the input
for Internet Draft publication. The section is in this document only
temporarily: it will soon move to its own page managed by someone yet to be determined. ]]]</t>

<t>[[[ Description of the transition from the current text format to also allowing
v3 XML. ]]]</t>

<t>[[[ Description of what will and won't be allowed in input XML. ]]]</t>

<section title="The Draft Processor">

<t>The Draft Processor will handle input differently than the RFC Processor.
For example, some XML that is valid for Internet Drafts will not be valid for canonical
RFCs, so the Draft Processor can be set to give warnings for those features but the RFC Processor
can be set to give hard errors. </t>

<t>The Draft Processor will help in the transition from the v2 format to the v3 format. A
user could request that the Draft Processor convert a v2 document to v3, using the new features of
v3 where appropriate, and removing the parts that are no longer supported.
The processor might be able to fully convert a v2 document to v3, or it might have to only
give advice on some of the v2 features that could not be automatically converted.</t>

<t>The Draft Processor should have a mode that mimics the RFC Processor's restictive mode,
but that instead gives warnings instead of hard errors.
The Draft Processor should also produce interim versions of the non-canonical representations
so that authors can see how their XML might later be rendered;
and to convert documents that use the v2 format to v3.</t>

</section>

<section title="Processor Instructions">

<t>In the v2 format, XML PIs were used for a wide variety of tasks,
including changing some formatting of the text outputs, adding information to HTML versions
of Internet Drafts, and specifying other instructions to processors. In the v3 format, a much
smaller set of PIs is supported for the Draft Processor and Private Processors. It is important
to note that canonical RFCs will not contain any PIs.</t>

<t>The following PIs will be supported by the Draft Processor:

<list style="symbols">

<t>editing -- When set to "yes", causes the processor to insert reference numbers throughout the output files to
allow ease of referral to particular paragraphs or artwork in the text. The default is "no".</t>

</list></t>

<t>The following PIs will not be supported by the Draft Processor, but are included so that Private
Processors have a common way of referring to them:

<list style="symbols">

<t>comments -- When set to "yes", causes all &lt;<x:ref>cref</x:ref>&gt; elements to be rendered
in the output files. The default is "yes".</t>

<t>linefile -- Causes the processor to emit more detailed information about which line of which input file
caused an error or warning.</t>

</list></t>

<t>Note that a Private Processor can have PIs not from this list.</t>

</section>

</section>

